Zoltan Kiss fonds
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department
Zoltan Kiss fonds
[196-] - 1981
F-48
Q100152814
7.5 cm of architectural plans and drawings
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department Maggie Benston Student Services Building, Rm. 0400 8888 University Dr. Burnaby British Columbia Canada V5A 1S6 Telephone: 778.782.3805 Email: archives@sfu.ca http://www.sfu.ca/archives
Kiss, Zoltan
Zoltan S. Kiss is one of the contributors to the architecture of Simon Fraser University. He was responsible for designing and building the Academic Quadrangle according to design specifications outlined by Erickson and Massey, the architects responsible for the overall design of the university. Kiss built the Academic Quadrangle in two phases, starting the first phase in 1964 and finishing the second phase in 1967.
Zoltan S. Kiss was born in Menfocsanak, Hungary in 1924. He studied at the Technical University of Hungary in Budapest during the war, and then went to Denmark to continue his studies. He later moved to Canada and attended the University of British Columbia where he completed a degree in architecture in 1951. Kiss worked for Thompson Berwick Pratt from 1953 to 1962. In 1963 Kiss submitted an entry to the contest to design the new university that would be built on top of Burnaby Mountain. His design finished in third place. According to contest parameters, the top five winners would each be given a contract to build a section of the campus according to the winner's overall design. Kiss chose the Academic Quadrangle, and incorporated his own ideas and innovations with Erickson and Massey's concept. Kiss, upon winning third place in the competition, started his own practice. His other contributions to the architecture of Simon Fraser University include the President's house, student residences, and the pub.
published
Full
Published
Title of the fonds is based on the name of its creator.
Fonds consists of Zoltan Kiss's architectural drawings and plans for the Academic Quadrangle and student residences at Simon Fraser University.
The material was arranged by the Archivist.
Architectural drawings; Textual records; Buildings and structures
Ron Dies of the firm, Zoltan S. Kiss Architecture, donated the mounted architectural drawings to the SFU Archives in 2000. In 2006 Mr. Dies donated a second set of architectural plans to the Archives.
All accessions have been processed as of July 2006. No further accruals are expected.
For other material relating to the construction and architectural design of SFU see F-47 W. Randle Iredale fonds, F-46 Robert F. Harrison fonds, F-65 Patrick McTaggart-Cowan fonds, and F-11 Facilities Management fonds.
The files are open with no restrictions.
File list is available.
- Architectural plans, [196-] - 1981; F-48-1; 7.5 cm of architectural plans and drawings
  published
  Series consists of architectural drawings and plans for the Academic Quadrangle, including cafeterias, lunch rooms, and laboratories; plans for the west concourse; student residences, and the Men's residence.
  - Cover sheet and perspective view drawings of AQ, February 1964; F-48-1-0-0-1
    Textual records
    Open
  - Archictectural plans A1 - A37, February 1964; F-48-1-0-0-2
  - Drawing - AQ Showing Lunch Room Addition, [196-]; F-48-1-0-0-3
  - Drawing - Entrance to Lunch Room at Court Level, [196-]; F-48-1-0-0-4
  - Drawing - AQ Showing Lunch Room Addition at Court Level, [196-]; F-48-1-0-0-5
  - Drawing - Perspective View of AQ Looking North-East, [196-]; F-48-1-0-0-6
  - Drawing - Perspective View of AQ Looking North-West, [196-]; F-48-1-0-0-7
  - Drawing - Shell House, [196-]; F-48-1-0-0-8
  - Academic Quadrangle - Phase II, 1965 - 1966; F-48-1-0-0-9
  - Student Residences, 1966; F-48-1-0-0-10
  - Lunch Room at Court Level of Academic Quadrangle, 1966; F-48-1-0-0-11
  - Laboratory Additions to Academic Quadrangle, 1966; F-48-1-0-0-12
  - Men's Residence, 1966; F-48-1-0-0-13
  - SFU Quadrangle Building Cafeteria, 1968; F-48-1-0-0-14
  - SFU West Concourse, 1981; F-48-1-0-0-15